我饿死了
I'm starving.
那有可能是给我做的吗
Any chance that's for me?
不 是给老妈做的
Oh, no. It is for Mom.
我打算今晚做些坏决定
I'm planning on making some bad choices tonight,
我需要她站在我这一边
and I'm gonna need her on my side.
这种小算盘我从没实现过
I never realized the forethought
全都落空成了遗憾
that went into being a disappointment.
早啊 米奇舅舅 你来干什么
Hey, Uncle Mitch. What are you doing here?
什么干什么 今天可是米奇舅舅的生日欢乐日
What do you mean? It's Uncle Mitchell's Birthday Fun Day.
我们知道
We know!
当然啦
Yeah! Yeah!
你终于来兑现它了 我们好开心
We are so excited you are finally cashing this in.
我也是
Me too.
米奇舅舅上个生日的时候我们忘了送礼物
We forgot to get Uncle Mitchell a present for his last birthday.
所以我们想到了这个绝妙的主意
So, we came up with this great idea --
和我们共享欢乐一日的兑换券
A coupon for a fun day with the three of us.
这主意很完美 因为它不仅棒
It was perfect because it was so sweet
我们也不用真的去兑现
and we'd never have to do it.
我希望你准备好迎接第一个大惊喜了
I hope you're ready for your first big surprise!
准备好了
I am.
超级乐享煎蛋卷
It's a super-fun omelet!
是啊
Aww! Uh, yeah!
如果你在纳闷这究竟有什么超级乐享的
And if you were wondering what is so super-fun about that,
这是因为随蛋附送的是
is that it comes with a -- a side of, uh...
卢克的煎蛋卷舞
Luke's omelet dance!
别害羞 你不是都练了一周吗
Don't be shy. You've been practicing all week. Come on.
好吧
Okay. Uh...
*今天是你的生日*
*It's your birthday*
*我是个煎蛋卷*
*I'm an omelet*
*今天是你的生日*
*It's your birthday*
*我是个煎蛋卷*
*I'm an omelet*
今天是你的生日
It's your birthday
这真是个现实的梦魇
This is a living nightmare.
他为何会直接过来
Why would he just show up?
他不应该给我们先打个招呼吗
Shouldn't he have given us some notice?
我似乎记得他打电话说过这事
I kind of remember him calling about it,
但我肯定会记在手机上
But I would've put it in my phone --
-记着呢 -果不其然
- Oh, there it is. - Of course.
天啊 我现在是应该在照看一只猫的
Oh, my god. I'm supposed to be cat-sitting.
我们得想出个好主意
We have to figure out something good.
他总是在我们生日第一个打电话祝贺
He's the first to call us on our birthdays,
他还总会送给我们超赞的礼物
and he always gets us amazing presents.
你有在听我讲话吗
Are you even listening to me?
一只猫不吃东西能活多久
How long can a cat go without eating?
海莉 他是世界上最棒的舅舅
Haley, he is the best uncle there is.
这玩意儿可不能是我们的礼物
This cannot be our present.
*今天是你的生日*
*It's your birthday*
*我是个煎蛋卷 今天是你的生日*
*I'm an omelet, it's your birthday*
我不清楚这是什么情况 但我喜欢
I don't know what's happening, but I love it.
-今天是你的生日 -今天是我的生日
- It's your birthday. - It's my birthday.
-我是个煎蛋卷 -你是个煎蛋卷
- I'm an omelet. - You're an omelet.
如果你再笑 我就自己弄我的指甲
If you're going to keep giggling, I'll do my own nails.
抱歉 只不过太好笑了 这种情景置换
I'm sorry -- it's just funny, the juxtaposition.
我懂 因为我是亚裔
I get it -- I'm Asian.
这可是种族歧视 大爸
It's racist, Daddy.
抱歉
Sorry.
莉莉 瞧瞧谁来了 我们可爱的加拿大房客
Lily, look who it is -- our lovely Canadian guests.
请进
Please come in.
楼上住的怎么样
How is everything upstairs?
楼上跟个宫殿一样
It's like a palace up there.
我还想着会不会遇到高登·平森特呢
I keep expecting to run into Gordon Pinsent.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
在楼下这里他不算是个大影星吗
Is he not a big movie star down here?
不算 但是感谢你们提供的瑞安·雷诺兹
No. But thank you for Ryan Reynolds.
还有件事 我们要去中国剧院
One little thing -- we're going to see the handprints
看星光大道的手印 我担心
at the Chinese Theater, and I'm worried
罗布穿短裤会显得不礼貌
it's going to look disrespectful if Rob wears shorts.
亲爱的 外面可有13度 我才不要穿长裤
Honey, it's 55 degrees out. I'm not wearing long pants.
没事的 那是好莱坞
You're fine. It's Hollywood.
还有人不穿裤子在那逛呢
There'll be people there with no pants.
你好 莉莉
Hi, Lily.
莉莉 跟蒙蒂打个招呼
Lily, say hi to Monte.
你好
Hi.
不好意思 她从来没这么害羞过
I'm...sorry. She's never this shy.
不 我们才不好意思 好像什么吓着她了
No, we'sorry. Seems like something scared her.
太有爱了
It was adorable.
莉莉很明显被加拿大的小蒙蒂迷住了
Lily was clearly smitten with that little Canadian Monte.
听出来歧视了 不好意思
Just heard that. Delightful.
这是我一直以来期待的成长里程碑
It was a rite of passage that I had been looking forward to --
我女儿的初恋
My daughter's first crush.
我想去支持帮助她
And I wanted to be there for her
因为当年没有人支持帮助我
in a way that no one was there for me.
也难怪 我的初恋是法院前
Of course, my first crush was on a statue
一座联邦政府将军的雕塑
of a confederate general in front of a courthouse.
也是在那一年他们挂上了
That's the same year they put up
"严禁攀爬"的牌子
The "Do Not Climb The Statue" signs.
抱歉来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
这衣服可以吗 车里还有另一件
Is this shirt okay? I got another one in the car.
只不过是吃顿午餐 淡定点
It's just lunch. Calm down.
你男友会喜欢的
Your boyfriend's gonna love it.
去年夏天 我和菲尔在卡波待了五天
Last summer, Phil and I went to Cabo for five days,
认识了汤姆和丽萨·德兰尼夫妇 玩得超开心
and we met Tom and Lisa Delaney, and we had so much fun,
每次他们过来我们都一定会跟他们聚会
we make sure to see them every time they're in town.
汤姆是一位十分成功的投资银行家
Tom's a hugely successful investment banker.
他参与很多的慈善活动
He does tons of charity work,
他能3小时24分跑完全程马拉松
he runs a marathon in 3:24,
他还会开自己的直升机
and he flies his own helicopter.
是啊 而丽萨呢
Yeah, and Lisa...
丽萨可真是个幸运的女士
Yeah, she is one lucky lady.
他们来之前
Before they get here,
你能不能答应我不要付账
can you promise me you won't pick up the check?
为什么
Why?
亲爱的 我喜欢他们
Oh, honey, I like them,
卡波之行后我们见了他们三次
but we've seen them three times since Cabo.
每次他们都会点最贵的东西
Every time, they order the most expensive stuff.
他们是我们认识最有钱的人
They are the richest people we know --
谢谢
Thank you.
然而我从来没见过他伸手去够账单
And yet I have not seen him reach for the check once.
汤姆不方便伸手够东西
Tom has trouble reaching for stuff.
他上大学投棒球伤了肩膀
He hurt his shoulder pitching in college.
NCAA第一分区
Division 1.
你之所以急着去付账
You feel a need to pick up the check
是因为你敬畏他
because you're intimidated by him
想要证明些什么
and you want to prove something.
怎么可能 我只不过嫌账单碍眼
That's crazy. I just don't like it when the bill sits there.
太尴尬了
It's awkward.
你不能一不喜欢什么东西
You can't just roll over on something
就往那东西上面摸啊
'cause it makes you feel uncomfortable.
随你便吧
Whatever you want.
美人你好啊
Hello, beautiful.
帅哥你好
Hi, handsome.
你们好啊
Hey, you two.
天啊 见到你们太高兴了
Hi! Oh, my gosh. It is so great to see you guys.
开瓶香槟吧
Let's get some champagne.
开吧
Let's do it.
我受够了
Okay, that's it.
如果你们那么讨厌它 就直说吧
If you hate it so much, just tell me.
好吧 你的古龙水糟透了
Fine. Your cologne is horrible.
你闻起来就好像脱衣女郎死在包厢里
You smell like a stripper died in a cabin.
我没在说古龙水
I'm not talking about my cologne.
这就是为何我会按兵不动等他自己说
That's why I hang back and wait for him to get specific.
我的胡子
My mustache.
我都留了好几周了
I've been growing it for weeks,
而你们俩安静得有点可疑
and the two of you have been conspicuously silent.
很好看
It's very dashing.
什么胡子
What mustache?
好吧 杰 好像我会相信你没看到似的
Right, Jay. Like I'm supposed to believe you didn't see it.
你赢了
You got me.
待会儿见 塞尔皮科
Check you later, Serpico.
塞尔皮科
Serpico!
你连那是谁都不知道
You don't even know who that is.
杰
Jay.
你拿着高尔夫球杆要去干什么
Where are you going with your golf clubs?
去黑夜中击球
Take a shot in the dark.
可我们约了玩伴啊
But we have a playdate.
真的吗 昨晚不是才玩过吗
Really? We just had one last night.
不是我不答应
Not that I'm saying no --
但今天这个节奏有点不太对啊
Just quicker turnaround than usual.
给乔约的玩伴
A playdate for Joe.
他父母都要来 所以你得在场
And both parents are coming, so you have to be here.
你在开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
这年头孩子们得预约
I mean, it's bad enough that these kids today
才能和别人玩已经够惨了
have to make a date to play with each other.
他们不能到大街上去踢铁罐
They can't go in the street and kick a can
或对着朋友杂志插页上的金·诺瓦克流口水
Or drool over a friend's centerfold of Kim Novak.
说点我能懂的好吗
Say something I understand.
我们为什么要坐在一旁看孩子玩呢
Why do we all have to sit around and watch our kids play?
因为大家现在都是这么做的
Because that's what people do now.
而且乔对此非常高兴呢
And Joe is very excited about it.
第一个真人朋友
His first real friend.
-歌洛莉亚 -怎么不行了
- Gloria... - What's the problem?
我很喜欢那个妈妈 而且大家都说
I like the mom, and everybody says
你和那爸爸有很多共同点
that you and the dad have a lot in common.
会很有趣的
It's going to be fun.
快请进 各位
Come in, everybody.
歌洛莉亚 这是我丈夫 马蒂
Gloria, this is my husband, Marty.
瞧瞧你啊
Look at you.
美得像一幅画
Pretty as a pinup.
那位传说中的幸运老公在哪儿呢
And where's the lucky husband I've been hearing about?
马蒂 那是杰
Marty, that's Jay.
真好 你的确也很老
Oh, good. You are old.
我还怕他们夸大其词了呢
I was scared they were exaggerating.
我可不想提前剧透
Um, so...I don't want to spoil any surprises,
不过 如果让你猜的话
But, uh, if you had to guess,
你觉得我们今天是要去干嘛呢
What -- what would you say we're doing today?
对 看看你能不能猜中我们的计划
Yeah, let's just see if you pick what we have planned.
我想想啊
Let's see.
天啊
Oh, my god.
是那个在奥克斯纳德的农场吗
Is it that farm in Oxnard
我 小卡和莉莉一起去摘草莓的那个地方
where Cam and Lily and I went strawberry-picking?
我们度过了最棒的
We had the most wonderful --
抱歉 不过你真的太会猜了
Sorry, but you are just so great at this game.
可是现在不是草莓的季节 所以肯定不是那
But it's not strawberry season, so it can't be that.
这也是为何我们没选那里
Which is exactly why we didn't pick that.
那再猜
Okay, so...guess again.
等等 我好像闻到了海水的味道
Wait -- do I smell the ocean?
你们是要带我去沙滩上那家超赞的卡尔顿酒店吗
Are you taking me to that fabulous Carlton's on the beach?
那儿有最
They have the most --
我们可没说一定是哦
Well, we're not making any promises,
不过这猜测挺靠谱的
but that would be a pretty good guess.
如果他们没有停业整修的话
If they weren't closed for renovations.
该死 继续想 米奇尔舅舅
Damn it! Think, Uncle Mitchell.
好像有点热了
It's getting a little warm in here.
你们介意开个车窗[打碎玻璃]吗
Do you mind if we crack a window?
除非我已经用头把它撞开了
Unless I've already done that with my head.
我们要停下来加油
We -- we need to stop for gas, okay?
别摘眼罩 米奇尔舅舅
Just keep your blindfold on, Uncle Mitchell.
好吧
Okay.
行 行吧
Fine. This is fine.
加满油
Fill 'er up!
好的 女士
Yes, Ma'am.
开玩笑吧
Seriously?
这样一直开着车乱转也不是办法
We can't just keep driving around.
我们得去个什么地方
We need to go somewhere.
集中精力 各位 米奇尔舅舅喜欢什么
Focus, people. What does Uncle Mitchell like?
不知道 基佬相关的 对吧
I don't know. Gay things, right?
你们能想到的最基的东西是啥
What's the gayest thing you can think of?
他的结婚对象
He's married to it.
快看
Hey, look.
每个人都爱追星 我们可以带他去星房观光
Everybody loves stars. We could take him on a tour.
开车转悠 到处看看房子
Driving around looking at houses
可算不上什么生日欢乐
isn't much of a birthday fun day?
我们需要更多时间
We need more time.
先把他敲晕吧
Let's knock him out.
查理兹·塞隆 哈里森·福特 哈莉·贝瑞
Charlize Theron, Harrison Ford, Halle Berry...
这些听起来都不是他的菜
None of these seem very Uncle Mitchell.
米奇尔舅舅喜欢什么呢
What does Uncle Mitchell like?
基佬的事物
Gay things.
那这个就是基王争霸赛里的霸主了
Then here's the mother lode.
芭芭拉·史翠珊[著名艺人] 太赞了
Barbra Streisand! Perfect!
等等 等等 等等
Okay, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
我们怎么知道这地图是不是真的
How do we know these maps are real?
你以为我拿些假地图来干这事业吗
You think I built this whole business on fake maps?
什么事业 你只有一块招牌和一张草坪躺椅
What business? You got a sign and a lawn chair.
我们可以抓紧吗 我可能还有只猫要喂
Can we wrap this up? I might still have a cat to feed.
菲尔估计拍了一百张我的沙滩照吧
Phil must have taken 100 pictures of me on the beach
就为了拍到我后面的裸女
just to get one shot of the topless women behind me.
你后面有裸女吗
There were topless women behind you?
账单放这了 你们准备买单叫我就好
Here you go. I'll just take this when you're ready.
好 谢谢
Oh, okay. Thank you.
你们今天还有什么安排吗
So, what do you two have planned for the rest of today?
没什么安排 真的
Nothing...really.
但如果你们要走了 这
But if you need to wind it up, it's --
不 我们不急
Nah. We're good.
那好 好
Yeah, good. Good.
你们呢 有计划什么好玩的吗 还是
Do you guys, uh, you have any fun trips planned or...
我计划着去趟卫生间
Well, I was planning on visiting the restroom,
顺利的话 可能犹如西班牙四月的雨季
and if all goes well, then maybe Spain in April.
再会 朋友
Adios, amigo.
与上帝同在
I vaya con dios!
管住你的手 朋友
You want to keep that hand, amigo?
法国真的太美了
And France was just beautiful.
自从诺曼底登陆日后我就没去过了
I hadn't been there since D-Day.
尽管再次走过那片沙滩
Took me the same amount of time
还是花了我那么久的时间
to get across that beach, though.
你也参过军吧
You were in the service?
有 不过是不同战争
Yeah, but different war.
和北朝鲜那次吧 我也参加了
Oh, Korea. Me too.
不 是下一场[越战] 继续猜
No, next war. Keep going.
谁要吃奶酪呢
Anybody want some cheese?
我吃不了 心血管不太好
Not me. Gums up the old ticker.
杰懂的
Jay knows about that.
不懂 我可爱吃奶酪了
No idea. Love the stuff.
吃杏仁小心点
Just be careful with the almonds.
不然假牙可能会咬坏掉
You may break the denture.
我这不是假牙 是种植牙
Uh, it's not a denture. It's an implant.
这个我们都说过几次了
How many times have we been over this?
你也容易忘东忘西 对吧
You forget stuff, too, huh?
我从来不健忘
I never forget anything.
在商场停车 我们还要拍张照记下位置
When we park at the mall, we have to take a picture.
杰 歌洛莉亚说你上一段婚姻也有孩子
Jay, Gloria tells me you have kids from your first marriage.
马蒂也是
So does Marty.
是啊 我最大的孩子有66岁
Yeah. My oldest is, uh, 66.
她去年去世了
Was. She passed last year.
我很遗憾
Oh, I'm so sorry.
那还年轻 怎么去世的
Well, that's young. What was it?
自然过世的
Natural causes.
我觉得都要怪压力过大
I blame most of it on stress.
现在的压力比过去大多了
So much more pressure than there was years ago.
回想我们那年代
Back in our day --
不同年代 我们不是一个年代
Different day. Not the same day.
事实上跟你去世的女儿差不多年代
Actually more your dead daughter's day.
愿她安息
May she rest in peace.
老妈 我们得谈谈
Mom, we need to talk.
你在这干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
你应该在上面看孩子的
You're supposed to be watching the kids.
韦斯利对乔会有不良影响的
Wesley is a bad influence on joe.
他很粗鲁又没礼貌
He's rude and disrespectful,
而且我觉得你得趁早扼杀了这段友情
and I think you should nip this friendship in the bud.
他取笑你的胡子 对吧
He made fun of your mustache, didn't he?
哪有四岁小孩还会知道"稀疏"这词
What kind of 4-year-old knows the word "Wispy"?
曼尼 看着我
Manny, look at me.
都这么近了 我还是没看到他胡子
This close, and I still couldn't see it.
再留久一点吧 好吗
It's just for a little while longer, okay?
好吧
Fine.
但是如果他们惹我的话 我也不会放过他们
But if they mess with me, I'm gonna mess with them.
你每天晚上要起来尿几次
How many times a night do you have to get up to pee?
我差不多四五次
I'm up to four or five.
我可不用 老前辈 最多两次
Not me, old-timer. Twice tops.
上个月有一次 我一整晚都没起过夜
Once last month, I even slept through the night.
我现在要去喝酒了
Now, I'm gonna refresh this
因为我没什么好担心的
'cause I got nothing to worry about.
我竟然真的跟那个混蛋
I'm literally in a pissing contest
在比尿尿次数
with the son of a bitch.
为什么我们要用上等的瓷器用餐呢
Why are we eating off the good china?
因为我们午餐有客人
Because we're having company for lunch.
谁要来啊
Who's coming?
好吧 我邀请了楼上的蒙蒂和他家人
Okay, I invited Monte and his family from upstairs.
什么 为什么
What?! Why?!
因为当爸爸的看出他女儿对人动心了呀
Because a daddy can tell when his little girl has a crush.
我不知道你在讲什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
莉莉 你要去哪儿
Hey, Lily, where are you going?
我希望你能放心地跟我聊这些
Look, I want you to be able to talk to me
感情这类的事情
about this kind of stuff.
对别人有感觉
It's completely natural and healthy
是很自然也很健康的
to have feelings for someone.
而且你知道吗 我觉得他也喜欢你
And you know what? I think he likes you, too.
你只要勾他一下 懂吗
You just have to draw him out, you know?
-稍微挑逗下 -怎么做
- Flirt a little. - How?
你就坐到他面前
Uh, well, you just sit down in front of him,
望着他的双眼 甜甜地笑上一个
look him straight in the eye, put a big smile on your face,
再问他些问题
and ask him some questions,
比如 你有什么兴趣爱好吗
like, "So, do you have any hobbies?
加拿大真有人们说的那么美吗
Is Canada really as beautiful as they say it is?
你喜欢培根吗
Are you a fan of the bacon?"
你干嘛要那样眨眼
Why are you blinking like that?
因为我要给他传递信号啊
Well, because I'm sending him signals.
还有什么呢
Okay, what else?
一定要称赞他的着装
Definitely compliment him on his outfit,
他讲笑话一定要笑
laugh at his jokes.
如果笑话不好笑呢
What if they aren't funny?
宝贝儿 撒了笑料就不是鲜肉了
Oh, honey, the cute ones rarely are.
上帝可不会什么都赋予
God doesn't give with both hands.
可不要乐出心脏病来
Okay, do not have a heart attack,
当你摘下眼罩时
but when you take off your blindfold,
你将看到的不是别人
you will be standing in front of none other
而正是传奇巨星
than the legendary superstar...
-谁 -大名鼎鼎的
- Who? - the one and only...
-谁 -芭芭拉·史翠珊
- Who? - Ms. Barbra Streisand--
我的天
Oh, my!
的家
's house.
你们当真吗 她真住这里吗
Oh, are you serious? She actually lives here?
难以置信
I can't believe it.
快瞧 她家大门开了
Dude, look. Her gate is open.
我们应该给你在她家车道上照张相
We should get a picture of you in her driveway.
这样的生日礼物岂不是赞上天了
How awesome of a birthday fun day gift would that be?
这样的话 胡娇绝对嫉妒死了
Okay. You know what? Pepper would die.
他为了《燕特尔》给自己办了第二次犹太受戒礼
He loved "Yentl" so much, he had a second Bar Mitzvah.
来照吧
Okay, let's -- let's do it.
站到房子前面
Okay, right in front of the house.
棒极了
Yeah. This is fantastic.
*胡娇 你听到了吗*
*Pepper, can you hear me?*
*胡娇 你看到了吗*
*Pepper, can you see me?*
*胡娇 我站在车道上*
*Pepper, I am standing in the driveway*
不好意思 你们在干什么
Excuse me. Can I help you?
实在抱歉 我们刚刚在
I'm so sorry. We were just --
天啊 你是雷·利奥塔[美国演员]
Oh, my god. You're Ray Liotta.
他真是她的大粉丝诶
He really is a big fan.
连她园丁的名字都知道
He even knows the name of her gardener.
《好家伙》[90年电影]
"Goodfellas"?
《散弹露露》[90年电影]
"Something Wild"?
《梦幻成真》[89年电影]
"Field of dreams"?
-没看过 -那年头我们都还没出生呢
- Never seen it. - Okay, we're really not that old.
雷·利奥塔是一位很好的演员
Look, Ray Liotta is a very fine actor,
我们占用了他太多的时间
And we have taken up enough of his time.
别不停地重复我的全名
Stop saying my full name
搞得好像你不提他们就不知道我是谁似的
like you have to keep telling them who I am.
等等 你和芭芭拉·史翠珊住一起吗
So, wait -- you live with Barbra Streisand?
你有地图吧
Y-y-you got the map.
她十五年前在这里住过两个月
She lived here for about 2 months 15 years ago.
你觉得那些混蛋会更新这些玩意儿
You think the bastards would update these things
显示目前住在这里的影星是谁吗
to reflect the current movie-star owners.
谢谢 走吧 孩子们
Thank you. Come on, kids.
很抱歉打扰了您
We're very sorry to have bothered you.
不 不 我不想你们空手而归
No, no, no. I don't want you to leave empty-handed.
过来拍张自拍吧
Come on in for a selfie.
好吧 给你
All right. Um... Here. O-okay.
等你们看过我的电影之后
When you see my movies later,
就会意识到这可是个特殊的时刻
you're gonna realize that this is a special moment.
来吧 茄子
Come on. And "Cheeeeese"!
看到没 这可是老演员微笑的秘诀
See? That's an old actor's trick for a perfect smile.
只不过只有我和你在笑 你们都没笑
Except you and I are smiling. You guys aren't smiling.
怎么一回事
W-what's the matter?
不是你的问题 利奥塔先生
It's not you, Mr. Liotta.
我们只是觉得让自己的舅舅失望了
We just really feel like we let our uncle down.
我们本应给他准备一个特殊的生日
We were supposed to plan a special day for his birthday,
可我们彻底失败了
and we totally flaked.
我们真的很抱歉
We're so sorry.
我们想了很久到底该把你带去哪里
We tried to figure out where to take you,
也知道你有多么地喜欢芭芭拉·史翠珊
and we know how much you love Barbra Streisand.
你总是送给我们最棒的礼物
You always give us the most awesome gifts.
我们逊毙了
We suck.
别这么说
Don't say that.
煎蛋卷舞到第二段时
I kind of figured you didn't have anything
我就大概知道你们什么都没准备了
by the second verse of the omelet dance.
我可是零基础
Hey, I've had no training.
但当我看到你们为了让我开心而那么卖力时
But then I saw how hard you were trying to make me happy,
我真的是很喜欢和你们在一起
and I just love hanging out with you guys.
再说了 我还见到了雷·利奥 雷
Plus, I did get to meet Ray Lio-- Ray.
你也会见到芭芭拉的
You're also gonna meet Barbra.
开什么玩笑
What? No.
我本来也要去她家一趟的
I've been meaning to go by her house anyway.
我这儿有一堆她的邮件
I've got a bunch of her mail.
不用这么麻烦你了
Oh, you don't have to do that.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
你让我想起了
You remind me of --
我小时候爱着的一个人
of someone that I loved when I was a kid.
我也有个逗逼舅舅
I had a funny uncle, too.
你真是太热情了
This is so nice of you.
我得承认
Well, I must admit,
请你们来其实是有点自己的小打算
I-I have a little bit of an ulterior motive.
我觉得莉莉看上你们家那个了
I think Lily has a giant crush on your little guy.
我有点想给他们牵红线
I kind of wanted to set them up.
我这人特别喜欢搞浪漫
I know -- I'm a hopeless romantic.
太有爱了
Oh! That's so cute!
我还记得我的初恋 那是在夏令营
I remember my first crush. It was at summer camp.
我住在多伦多 他是埃德蒙顿来的
I lived in Toronto, and he was from Edmonton,
也算是有缘无分
So it was very star-crossed.
有点像我们的小罗密欧与朱丽叶
Just like our little Romeo and Juliet.
他是我爱过的第一个男孩
He was the first boy I ever loved.
比利·麦克林
Billy Macklin.
天啊 我都多少年没想起过他了
God. I haven't thought of him in years.
你有什么兴趣爱好吗
Do you have any hobbies?
我喜欢攀岩
Well, I like rock climbing.
我收集宠物小精灵
I collect Pokemon --
我听说加拿大挺不错
I hear Canada's nice.
你喜欢培根吗
Do you like bacon?
话说起来 我要去
Okay, you know what, I'm just gonna --
夏天一过就开始出现问题了
After that summer, things got pretty rough.
爹死了 娘也开始酗酒
Dad died, Mom started drinking.
太难承受了
It was a lot to handle.
我喜欢你的衬衫 是新的吗
I love your shirt. Is it new?
我想这衬衫的年岁比你还大
Oh, I think this shirt's older than you are.
莉莉 到卧室去 跟你有话说
Okay, Lily, can I see you in the bedroom, please?
比我还大 罗布 你可笑死我了
Older than I am -- oh, Rob, you're killing me!
我们去去就回
Okay, we'll be right back.
别骚了
And enough.
你刚才在干什么
What are you doing out there?
你教我的啊
What you told me.
我觉得进展不错
I think it's going pretty good.
我还以为你看上的是蒙蒂
I thought your crush was on Monte.
你不能和成年人调情啊
You can't flirt with a grown man.
可你说过
But you said --
不 这样不好
No. It's not appropriate.
不 我再也不要和男生说话了
Oh, no! I'm never talking to a boy ever again!
莉莉 你没必要感到羞愧
Lily, you have nothing to be ashamed of.
要怪就怪我吧
If -- if anything, this is -- this is my fault.
我还以为你喜欢蒙蒂 是我的错
I thought you meant Monte, and I confused you.
我能告诉你个秘密吗
Can I...tell you a little secret?
不
No!
当我对初恋采取行动时
Well, when I made a move on my first crush,
情况完全失控了
it went way worse.
那天是新年前夜 我跑去给他一个吻
It was New Year's Eve, and I went to give him a kiss,
结果舌头黏在他脸上了
and my tongue froze to his cheek.
为什么冻上了
Why did it freeze?
天太冷 而且他还是铜做的
It was cold, and he was made out of bronze,
我再也不想说这事儿了
And I don't want to talk about this anymore.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
马蒂说我们这年纪的人做不了十个仰卧起坐
Marty said guys our age can't do 10 sit-ups.
我不记得说过这话 但像是我说的话
I don't remember saying it, but it sounds like me.
杰 麻烦你过来一下
Jay, may I speak with you for a moment?
好
All right.
糟了
Ah, crap!
让我帮你
Uh, here. L-let me help you.
我要倒了
I'm going down!
维琪
Vicky!
你今天是怎么回事
What is wrong with you today?
我受够了马蒂把我
I'm sick of Marty lumping me
跟他们一个年龄段的人混为一谈
into the same age category as him.
说什么 像我们这样的人 我们那时候
"Guys like us," "Back in our day."
我可是战后婴儿潮出生的人
I'm a baby boomer, for god's sake.
我记得《点燃我的火》[60年代金曲]全部歌词
I know all the words to "Light My Fire."
杰 你不能只再为自己着想了
Jay, you have to stop thinking only about you.
我知道 我改为乔着想
Yeah, I know, I know. I should think about Joe.
不 为我
No -- Me!
你知道我和维琪
Do you know that Vicky and I
是班上年纪最大的妈妈吗 比别人大得多
are the oldest moms in the class -- by a lot?
所以呢
So?
你也许不知道
This might surprise you,
变老对女人也是件烦心事
but aging is also a big deal for women.
我需要维琪做我的朋友
I need Vicky to be my friend.
在那群年轻妈妈里我觉得很不自在
I feel out of place around all those young moms.
如果你不喜欢她老公
And if you don't like her husband,
也许她就不喜欢我了
maybe she'll stop liking me.
歌洛莉亚 我在努力 但是
Gloria, I'm trying, but it's --
至少你不是最老的爸爸
At least you're not the oldest dad.
你就不能享受这一点吗
Can't you enjoy that?
上一次你作为
When was the last time
年轻人亮相是什么时候
that you were the young stud in the room?
我把我妈送进养老院那回
When I put Mom in that nursing home.
就那么一小会儿
That was quite a rush.
你能更友善一点吗
So, are you going to be nice?
好 他也没那么差啦
Yes. He's not a bad guy.
再说啦 我要忍他的日子
And really, how much longer
也没剩多少了
am I gonna have to put up with him?
不 杰 不准这么说
Ay, no, Jay. Don't say that.
你会很长寿的
You're going to live a long life.
不是我 我说的是外面那老头
Not me! Grandpa out there!
他能听见
He can hear you.
听见什么
Hear what?
你们又在谈论我的胡子吗
You were talking about my mustache again?
不 曼尼 我们喜欢你的胡子
No, Manny. We love your mustache.
搞笑
Oh, hilarious.
我把胡子都剃了你说你喜欢
Tell me you like it now that I've shaved it off!
母亲是黑人 父亲是白人 但我没见过他
Black mother and white father, but I've never met him.
这才是社会上该流传的故事
That's a story that should be out there more --
白人父亲抛妻弃子[一般是黑人父亲]
White fathers who abandon their families.
还有什么 还有什么
What else? What else?
这位是沃尔特
So, this is Walter.
就好像我之前接杰罗米的班一样
Just as I took over for Jeremy when his shift ended,
他要来接我的班了
he'll be taking over for me.
或者说你们准备好买单了
Unless you're ready?
我觉得我们还得聊会儿 谢啦
I think we're still talking. But thanks.
沃尔特 我能到那边问你个问题吗
Walter? Could I ask you a quick question right over there?
我也马上就回来
I'll be right back, too.
我需要跟我老公聊两句 谢谢
I just need a minute alone with my husband. Thank you.
这单绝对不能由你来付
There is no way you are paying that bill.
放在那儿都多久了
It has been out there forever,
他手都没往钱包上伸过 装都不装一下
and he hasn't even pretended to reach for his wallet.
太折磨人了 克莱尔
This is torture, Claire.
我愿意付任何账结束这一切
I'll pay anything to end it.
挺住
Stay strong.
我挺不住 你嫁给了一个挺不住的男人
I'm weak. You married a weak man!
把卡给我 把卡
Give it to me. Give it --
菲尔
Phil --
不 沃特尔 沃特尔
No! Walter! Walter!
沃特尔 不
Walter! D'ohh!
好吧 我说开了吧
Okay. Here's the thing.
-我喜欢和你们 -不 克莱尔 不
- We like hanging out -- - No, Claire! No!
我知道是怎么一回事
I know what this is about.
汤姆 你该把账付了 太没礼貌了
Tom, you should have paid the check. It's rude.
他没有不礼貌 他很好 是我必须付账
He's not rude. He's wonderful. I had to pay.
为什么
Why?
菲尔 你不准再说了
Phil, don't you say another word!
看到没 告诉过你了
Ow! See? I told you.
这究竟是怎么一回事
What the hell is going on here?
-什么事都没有 -菲尔
- Nothing. - Phil?
好吧 如果你非得知道
Fine -- if you have to know
我生活里的每一个细节的话
every last detail about my life...
我在卡波和汤姆打赌输了 欠了他五顿饭
I lost a bet to Tom in Cabo. Now I owe him five meals.
-说完了 -就这回事
- There -- we're done. - That's it.
那你为什么不早说
Why didn't you just say that?
没为什么
Th-- there's no reason.
打的什么赌
What...was...the bet?
菲尔 我认真的 不准再说话了
Phil, I mean it -- don't say another word.
她们迟早会猜到的 汤姆
They're gonna figure it out, Tom.
-她们怎么可能猜到 -她们会猜到的
- How could they figure out, Phil? - They're gonna figure it out.
我们喝鸡尾酒喝醉了 然后我们想弄清
We were drunk on margaritas, and we wanted to find out
谁的老婆能吃更多的蟋蟀
whose wife would eat the most crickets.
-什么 -什么
- What?! - What?!
看来她们并没可能猜到 菲尔
Doesn't seem like they were circling that, Phil.
你们就抓了蟋蟀
You were just g-grabbing crickets
偷偷往我们的食物里放吗
and sneaking them into our food?
不是活蟋蟀 烤的
Not live ones. They were roasted.
天啊
Oh, my god!
你们真恶心
You're disgusting people.
你没看到好的一面 亲爱的
You're missing the silver lining here, honey.
我输掉了
I lost the bet.
所以我没吃成蟋蟀吗
So I didn't eat crickets?
你吃了三只
You ate three.
丽萨吃了六只
Ohh! Lisa had six.
六只
Six?!
你让我吃四只不就已经可以赢了吗
You could've won with four!
亲爱的 我不能冒这个险
Baby, baby, I couldn't take that chance.
我要让你们俩好好地思考一下
I'd like to give you two a little something to think about.
你们吃的大部分食物都是我们准备的
Most of the food you eat is prepared by us.
或者是私人厨师准备的
Or by our private chef.
但我懂你意思 你继续说
But I-I like where you're going.
下一回你们俩大嚼汉堡
Next time you take a bite of a big, juicy burger
或者吃意大利面时
or dig into a bowl of spaghetti,
里面会有一些特殊的佐料
there's gonna be an extra special ingredient in there,
绝对不是妻子的爱意
and it won't be love.
你这次放了几只
How many did you get this time?
两只蟋蟀
Two crickets.
这才更有道理嘛
Okay, this makes more sense.
芭芭拉绝对不会让自家大门敞开的
Barbra would never leave her gate wide open.
我家的门是坏了关不上
They're broken, okay?
别让我后悔带你来这
Don't make me regret bringing you here.
谁
Hello?
芭芭拉在家吗 我是雷·利奥塔
Is Barbra home? It's Ray Liotta.
演过《好家伙》
You know, from "Goodfellas."
-《散弹露露》 -还有《梦幻成真》
- "Something Wild." - "Field of Dreams."
我知道他是谁 怎么了 雷
Oh, I know who he is. What's up, Ray?
芭芭拉 我这有些你的邮件
Barbra, I have some of your mail
寄到你原来在西达赫斯特的住处了
from when you used to live over at Cedarhurst.
我这还有个朋友想
And I have a friend here that would like --
把邮件放到门口 我叫人去拿
Just leave the mail by the gate. I'll send someone down.
好的 但是
O-okay, but --
还有什么事
Oh. There's more?
史翠珊小姐 你好 我叫米奇尔·普里契特
Uh, Ms. Streisand, hi. My -- my name is Mitchell Pritchett,
不知道多少年前我就是你的粉丝了
And I have been a fan of yours since I can't even remember,
您的风雅和正直
And -- oh, your artistry and integrity
影响了我的整个人生 我
has inspired me my whole life, and I just --
真不敢相信我在和你说话
I can't even believe I'm talking to you right now.
拜托 我只是个普通人 和你一样
Please. I'm just a regular person, like you.
我穿裤子都需要有人帮我一条腿一条腿往上套
I have people put on my pants one leg at a time.
太好笑了
That's so funny.
芭芭拉 今天是他的生日
Barbra, today is his birthday!
实际上应该是三周前
Well, technically, it was three weeks ago.
-别搞砸了 -抱歉
- All right, you're blowing it. - Sorry.
你的声音很甜美 米奇尔
You sound very sweet, Mitchell.
我在想 你也许可以送给他一个特殊的礼物
I-I was thinking maybe as a special treat, you could --
我才不要对着门禁话筒唱歌 雷
I'm not singing into my gate, Ray.
很荣幸跟您聊天
Well, it was very nice to talk to you.
我只有一个小小的问题
I did have a quick question about --
再见
Goodbye.
没事
It's fine.
等我讲这个故事的时候
When I tell the story,
结尾是她给我唱了生日歌
it ends with her singing "Happy Birthday."
糟糕 过三点了
Oh, shoot. It's past 3:00.
怎么了 赶不上晚饭了吗
What's wrong? You late for dinner?
杰
Jay.
没事 如果我们现在走 我们
Honey, it's okay. If we leave now, we --
不 我错过了
No, no, I missed it.
你错过什么了
What did you miss?
这周老电影频道上是舞蹈电影特映周
It's Fred and Ginger Week on TCM.
今天播的《欢乐时光》[36年电影]我忘了录
They're showing "Swing Time". And I forgot to record it.
让我给你介绍一个新发明 叫网飞
Let me tell you about a little innovation called Netflix.
你绝对不会再错过任何一部电影了
You'll never miss another movie again.
-真的吗 -对天发誓
- Really? - Hand to God.
你在电脑上挑一部电影
You pick a film on your computer.
三天之后 电影光碟就邮到你家了
Three days later, there's a disk in your mailbox.
你可得跟上科技的脚步啊 马蒂
You got to stay up with technology, Marty.
谢谢
Wow. Thanks.
你能相信他居然不知道网上直播吗
Can you believe he doesn't know about streaming?
如果没那玩意儿 我还不如死了好
If I ever get that out of touch, kill me.